# JOPAUL KARRIYATHI

104 Ground Floor, Leicester, LE2 0QS
United Kingdom
Mobile: +44 (0)7775314477
Email: Jk212@student.le.ac.uk

#### **PROFILE**

A highly self-motivated General Engineering student with strong analytical, problem solving and IT skills seeks a challenging engineering placement, one that will make the best use of my existing skills and experience. An international student with highly developed communication skills and a strong understanding of technical language who would be a great asset to your team.

#### **ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS**

2011 – Present	<b>BEng General Engineering with one year Industry</b> , University of Leicester AutoCAD& Solid Works, Mechanics of Structures, Electrical Engineering, Electromagnetism and Electronics, Design and Management
2010 – 2011	Access to science Diploma, Oxford & Cherwell College Maths (Distinction), Physics (Distinction), Chemistry (Merit)
2008 – 2010	NVQ 1&2 Performing Engineering Operations, Oxford &Cherwell College Wiring and Testing Electrical Equipment and circuits, Producing component using hand fitting techniques Working Safely, Efficiently and Effectively in Engineering
2004 – 2006	BTEC First Diploma in Engineering (FP Grado Medio en Equipos e Instalaciones Electrotécnicas) Don Bosco, College Salesiano, Granada, Spain
2003 – 2004	GCSE (E.S.O.) IES Alhambra, Granada, Spain Spanish Literature, Mathematics, Science, IT, English

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### 07/2012 - 07/2012 Training, South Leicestershire College

- Day to day works involved dismantling, replacing and assembling engineering equipment and tools.
   Making components such as Bevel Gauge using hand tools, fitting techniques, soldering circuit boards, wiring and testing electrical circuits and fault finding.
- The tasks were carried out using technical information such as technical drawings and communicating with qualified technicians.
- The experience helped me to improve my technical skills particularly planning, problem solving and hand skills. It also enabled me to widen my knowledge of Health & Safety at work and perform practical work in a safe and appropriate manner.

### 07/2006 - 08/2009 Technical Assistant, J.Marin Installations Frio Calor SA

- Worked alongside experienced technicians installing air-conditioning units, assisting on maintaining and repairing compressors, preparing necessary tools and equipment (ammeter, vacuum pump and welding equipment) on site, ensuring the work area was clean and safe at all times.
- As I progressed the role helped to develop the following skills; practical experience, attention to detail, communicating with senior technicians and safe working practices.

#### **KEY SKILLS**

### Computational

Confident using programmes within Microsoft Office such as Word, Excel, Power Point and Publisher to manipulate, organize and present data appropriately.

Good understanding of BS/ISO drawing standards and able to produce those using appropriate tools such as AutoCAD and Solid Works, also confident using MATLAB. Throughout my academic qualifications I have had to use these programmes to support my work.

### Problem Solving

Problem based learning at university has helped to develop strong analytical skills and a rigorous approach to solving problems and informed decision making. For instance, over the summer training period, in the workshop we were given an electrical circuit with fault in it, our task was to identify the faults and report to the senior technician. I analyzed the circuit and applied the circuit theory then used appropriate equipment such as voltmeter to check the correct readings according to the theory. The process helped to find out the fault in the circuit.

### Organization & Time Management

Extensive organizational and time management skills developed as mature student in both an academic and work environment. This enables me to achieve maximum output in minimum time, as well as handle a number of activities simultaneously. I am able to plan and organize myself to ensure that coursework is delivered to a high standard and meet deadlines; I am currently on track to achieve a 2:1 degree (+ 60%)

#### Communication

Confident communication skills achieved from diverse range of experience during the academic years, for example, undertaking presentations, written reports, assignments and projects. My verbal communication skill in Spanish has also improved having completed academic qualifications and engineering placement in Spain.

#### Teamwork

My personal strengths lie in my ability to work as part of a team during academic group assignments, project work and part time employment. I enjoy working collaboratively to achieve positive outcomes but am able to lead if required.

# Languages

Fluent in English and Hindi with a working knowledge of spoken Spanish. Knowledge of using technical level Spanish. Experienced in communication with colleagues from a diverse range of linguistic backgrounds.

# INTERESTS/POSITIONS OF RESPONSIBILITIES

- Volunteered in the London 2012 Paralympic Games Opening Ceremony.
- Member of the University of Leicester Football team: Play regularly for engineering football team and have supported the captain by arranging matches and players for league competitions.
- Enjoy watching Formula 1 racing show and Top gear

### **REFERENCES**

Professor Tanya Vladimirova Embedded Systems and Communications Research Group Project supervisor University of Leicester T: +44 (0)116 252 5372

Email: tv29@le.ac.uk

Rafa Valenzuela Profesor de Formación Profesional Colegio San Juan Bosco Calle Almuñécar, 9 18006 Granada

T: +34 958 81 16 11